How much do you have by the way, it's not bad,
Сколько у тебя кстати зарплата неплохая
it's how much 2,000 dollars I have in the
это сколько 2.000 долларов я имею в
social sphere, you work and
социальной сфере ты работаешь и
get 2,000
получаешь 2.000
dollars, well, I'll
долларов ну это я приу
multiply it by 10 times, well, let's do it less, let's
величи раз 10 Ну так меньше давайте так
say I get 50,000 rubles, so that's already
Допустим я получаю Ну 50.000 руб так уже
Hello, your eyes are ah,
Привет глаза у тебя
Thank you,
а Спасибо Ты
where are you from?  Well, I'm
откуда Ну я
afraid aggressive no no I see you're from
боюсь агрессивный не не я вижу ты из
Russia city just what
России город какой просто
and
а
North north what exactly Tyumen understood I
Север север кае именно Тюмень понял Я
myself come from Rostov
сам родом из Ростова
so I'm just trolling Ukrainians I put up the
вот я просто троллю украинцев я поставил
US flag hung it up and put it up as if I'm
флаг США повешал и поставил будто бы я
from Ukraine and troll them
из Украины и тролли их
and then showing the flag  Russia This is on the
а потом показывая флаг России Вот это на
number They are at you They are yelling at you
номере Они на тебя Они на тебя кричат
here Well, I don't really come across it No,
тут ну я как бы не сталкиваюсь Нет один
I once had this happen that I ran into
раз у меня было такое что я нарвалась на
A about Well, a Russian who lives
А про Ну россиянина который проживает
in the USA works as a pilot, he told
вка там в Штатах пилотом работает он
me like that Matyuk Well, I didn't really  I listened to
меня так Матюк Ну как бы я выслушала
his arguments so to speak
его аргументы так сказать
and his position but I didn't start to speak out
а позицию но не стала яро выступать
against him vehemently this is his position but it doesn't
против него это его позиция но меня она
concern me much your position What do you
мало касается ваша позиция Как вы
think  Crimea should remain with Russia
считаете Крым должен за Россией остаться
Or should we give it
Или мы должны его Украине отдать
back to Ukraine oh well, a provocative question How
назад а ну провокационный вопрос А как я
can I I'm not a politician to decide
могу я не политик чтобы решать
Whose
Чей это
region is this but from the point of
регион но с точки
view If you
зрения Если так
think about it, it's not that Crimea is ours or
подумать не то чтобы Крым наш или там
as they like to shout
как любят кричать
but Ukraine at the moment  it does not have an
но Украина на данный момент она не имеет
independent unit As such
самостоятельной единицы Как таковой на
today and politically it
сегодняшний день и политически она не
cannot give people
может дать людям
protection and any guarantees What is
защитить их и каких-то гарантий О чём
Russia talking about then at the moment Yes, it
Тогда Россия на данный момент Да она
can at least give some stability
может по крайней мере дать стабильность
Tell me What kind of stability does it have  you in the
Расскажите Какая стабильность у вас на
north with us I won't say anything about it
севере у нас я про это ничего говорить
That is, you don't have
не буду То есть у вас нет у вас
stable snow and
стабильно снег и
no in any case that's just how
нет ни в коем случае вот как раз-таки у
we have stability
нас есть стабильность
but something Like something don't like but
но что-то Нравится что-то не нравится но
nevertheless  No, at least I'm
тем не менее Нет я по крайней мере я в
confident in tomorrow And this is the main thing,
завтрашнем дне уверен А это главное
tomorrow will be Look,
завтрашний день будет Смотри завтрашний
tomorrow will be regardless of whether you will be
день будет независимо от того будешь ли
true How much is your salary, by the way,
правда Сколько у тебя кстати зарплата
not bad, that's
неплохая это
how much, well,
сколько
2,000 dollars I
м 2.000 долларов я
have, how many clients a day
имею сколько в день клиентов
And I don't work with  people
А я не работаю с людьми
What a
Что за
perversion no It's the opposite good I don't
извращение нет Это наоборот хорошо я не
like people I don't  I love working with them And
люблю людей я не люблю с ними работать А
what do you
кем ты
do for a living? Well, let it
работаешь неважно Ну пусть это будет
be my little one Well, in what
будет маленькая моя та Ну в какой
sphere Well, I'm not a
сфере Ну я не
public sector employee in the social sphere you get
социальной в социальной сфере получаешь
dollars Well, I
долларов ну это я
exaggerated 10 times so less and 10 times
преувеличил раз 10 так меньше а раз 10
Yes, you know, a man also
Да это знаешь мужчина тоже
exaggerates his  salary and you
преувеличивает свою зарплату и ты
exaggerated
преувеличил
No, not 10 times but how many
Да нет не раз в 10 а в сколько
times Well,
раз Ну процентов
probably
наверное на
20 percent 30 somewhere like that
20 30 где-то так
Yeah That is, you get if 20% 1/5
Угу То есть ты получаешь если на 20% 1/5
Let's subtract you
Давай отнимем ты получаешь
get 00
выходит 00
dollars or subtract another
долларов или ещё отнимаем
20% the rate is  today how much
20% курс на сегодняшний день сколько
100 Well then yes let
100 А ну тогда да
's reduce it let's reduce it let's drop it some more
уменьшаем уменьшаем давай ещё скинем
in short 40,000 rubles Let's uh 1,200
короче 40.000 руб Давай э-э 1.200
dollars Well reduce it some more let's
долларов Ну ещё умень ещё
reduce it some more no well 1,200 dollars - that
уменьшаем нет ну 1.200 долларов - это
's 120,000 rubles let's reduce it there's no
получается 120.000 руб уменьшаем вобще
point in discussing wages at all
заработную плату обсуждать это смысла
let's reduce it honestly
нет ну давай давай по чесноку уменьшаем
so no well again I can respond
так Не ну опять-таки я могу ответный
ask a question How much do you get
вопрос задать Сколько Вы получаете
99,000 dollars your income is 99,000
99.000 долларов доход у вас 99.000
dollars Wow not bad Well in California this is
долларов Ого неплохо Ну в Калифорнии это
a small salary here in California I am a
небольшая зарплата у нас в Калифорнии Я
university teacher Well let's
преподаватель университета Ну давайте мы
finish with you we reduce it
всё-таки с вами закончим уменьшаем
means no no no 1,200 dollars but
значит не не не 1.200 долларов а
we reduce it not 120,000 rubles yes let's
уменьшаем не 120.000 руб да давайте
Reduce in
Уменьши в
uh if 80,000 rubles reduce further or not
ээ если 80.000 руб уменьшаем ещё или нет
8800 dollars
8800 долларов
reduce reduce No well how much no
уменьшаем уменьшаем Нет ну сколько нет
more
больше
no
нет
No come on already Tell me How much is your
Нет давай уже Говори Сколько у тебя
salary in dollars
зарплата
Well well okay let's say a thousand bucks
Ну ну ладно допустим штука баксов
exactly so it's monthly Ponya means
точно так это ежемесячно Поня значит
monthly
ежемесячно
100,000
100.000
rubles Well yes Well for me  it seems you are not quite
руб Ну да Ну мне кажется ты не совсем
sure Let's reduce it so that it
уверена Давай уменьшаем давай чтобы
is honest
по-честному было
and I can't say that it is less because
а я не могу сказать что меньше потому
m Here then the plus ones go, the
м Здесь идут тогда плюсовые идут
premium
премиальные
northern ones go No without the northern ones But at the top, as
северные Нет без северных А вот сверху
if here I
как бы здесь я
would lie that it is
совру что
less You are already saying I am a psychologist It's just that
меньше Ты уже говоришь я психолог Просто
I  I teach psychology at Sacramento State University
я преподаю психологию в университете
I see myself as I  I teach
Сакраменто я я вижу как я преподаю как
physiognomy How can you tell by facial expressions whether a
раз физиогномика Да как по мимике лица
person is lying or not And
определить человек врёт или нет И как
your facial expressions are very visible
раз у тебя очень сильно видно мимика
You are close and I see that you are lying
лица Ты близко и я вижу что обманываешь
I see that you are lying
я вижу что обманываешь
Oh
А ладно
okay Okay let it be I am lying
Хорошо пусть Яя обманываю
[music]
[музыка]
yeah let's do it this way Let's say I get  Well
да давайте так Допустим я получаю Ну
50,000 rubles so already 50 was 200,000 2000
50.000 руб так уже 50 было 200.000 2000
dollars now 500 dollars so 50B then
дол теперь 500 долларов так 50Б дальше
good Well what will this change
хорошо Ну и что это изменит
about
около
23,000 rubles there with kopecks goes No this is a
23.000 руб там с копейками идёт Нет это
living wage not lived if you are in the region
прожиточный не прожито если у вас регион
Well, you work for public sector employees in the
А ну вот вы вы работаете бюджетникам в
public sector so No  I'm not a public sector employee
бюджетной сфере так Нет я не бюджетник
now I told you I'm a social worker the
сейчас я же сказала я социалка
subsistence minimum in Russia in 2024
прожиточный минимум в России двадцать
was 17,000 rubles
был 17000 руб
1,773 rubles well that's according to the average wage in
1773 руб ну это по средней палате
Russia well what region are you in I
России ну а какой у вас регион Я сейчас
'll look at your region now
посмотрю по вашему региону
ok
хорошо
Yamalo-Nenets Autonomous Okrug
ЯНАО
21,706 rubles I  malaninsky yeah yeah that's it and there in the
21706 руб я маланинский да угу вот а там
north it's like 21,000 107 rubles
севера так 21.000 107 руб
No, not again how much did you say
Да не ещё раз сколько вы сказали
21,706 but no there
21706 а нет там 23
23,718 These are approved from January 1,
718 Это утверждённые от 1 января
twenty-fifth year Yeah, I get it you are
двадцать пятого года Ага понял вы
charged these salaries yes You are an
начисляется эти зарплаты да Вы
accountant No well what do you work
бухгалтер Нет ну а кем вы работаете
as What's the difference  what I work for is
Да какая разница кем я работаю это
not important but I was very interested that
неважно но мне очень интересно стало что
you work as a psychologist And how much
вы работаете психологом И сколько
practice do you already have in time
практики у вас занимает уже по времени
18 years of practice in 2 years will be
18 лет практики через 2 года будет
[music]
[музыка]
twentieth and did you graduate from the
двадцатом а заканчивали вы университет
University of Sacramento Sacramento
университет города Сакраменто Сакраменто
State University of
государственный университет штата
California It's
Калифорния
probably warm there Heat
Тепло там наверно
yes yes And now what kind of weather is it hot
Жара да да А сейчас какая погода жарко
you can envy from the Yamal-Nenets Autonomous Okrug You can
автономного округа Вы можете
envy Yes I think so too
позавидовать Да я тоже так думаю потому
because you can even
что вы даже Ростову можете
envy Rostov Yes I can
позавидовать Да я и Крыму могу
envy Crimea And here is such an
позавидовать А вот такой как бы
interesting question where are you
интересный вопрос вы куда отдыхать в
planning to go on holiday this year from  of his
этом году планируете ехать из своего
Yamal Nenets Autonomous
Ямала Ненецкого автономного
Okrug
округа
nowhere
никуда
Why I don't know with such  with a big salary you
Почему не знаю с такой большой зарплатой
can go to Anapa for example,
можно съездить например в Анапу там
they say there are cheap trips there now
говорят сейчас дешёвые путёвки
But Anapa doesn't appeal to me why are there
А меня Анапа не привлекает почему там
oil stains there at all interesting ones you
мазутные пятна вообще интересные есть
can find
можно
right away Granite pebble you can find but somehow I'm
сразу Гранитный камушек можно найти но я
not in
что-то как-то не
a hurry Where did your arrogance
спешу А куда ваша спесь
go M what
делась М какая
kind of beach is it man
именно пляж мужчина
rock and roll
рокенрол
well maybe next year or
а ну может быть в следующем году или ещё
again next year or again
раз в следующем году или ещё ещё раз
next year yes we
следующею да мы как зарплату
didn't stint on salary so And here and maybe
не жали так И тут а может ещё в
next year
следующем
Yes no I'm somehow honestly
Да нет мне как-то честно
not interested not interested in
неинтересно неинтересно
resting No I'm not interested in resting
отдыхать Нет не интересно отдыхать
but I don't  I see this as such a
но я не вижу в этом ж такой прямо
necessity Well, yes, when there is not enough
необходимости Ну да когда не хватает
money for a vacation, then there is no need
денег на отдых то и необходимости нет
How money appears So for
Как появляются деньги Так у людей
some reason people immediately
почему-то сразу
find this
находится это
necessity Well, yes, probably But I dont have
необходимость Ну да наверно Но у меня не
that much money So Wait, you
так много денег Так Подождите вы же за
get for 1,000 dollars  Well, I have
1.000 долларов получаете Ну мне есть
somewhere to spend them, where do you
куда их тратить куда вы
spend them on everyday life, and what do you
тратите на повседневную жизнь а что вы
buy for everyday necessities, what are
покупаете повседнев необходи нужды какие
your essential needs? In the Yamalo-Nenets
у вас необходимые нужды В ямало-ненецком
Autonomous
автономном
Okrug, food
округе еда
[laughter]
[смех]
your entire salary goes on
у вас вся зарплата уходит на
food Well, you
еду Ну вы
mouth no wait housing and communal
рте нет подождите жилищно-коммунальные
services I still where are the most famous
услуги я ещ где ж известнейшие
Russian cheap communal services
Российская дешёвая коммуналка
And I dont know if anyone has it cheap I
А я не знаю у кого-то она есть дешёвая
dont know And what do you think if Putin
не знаю А как ты считаешь если бы Путин
sent money not to the war but to
отправлял деньги не на войну а на
salaries pensions development of regions it
зарплаты пенсии развитие регионов это
would be better
было бы лучше
m a and it seems to me Sometimes even too
м а мне и кажется Иногда даже слишком
many
много
are sent somewhere to war No no not to
отправляют куда на войну Да нет не на
war
войну
on pensions benefits all this is all for
на пенсии пособия вот это вот всё на
some kind of social development This is what
социальную какую-то развитость Вот это
irritates you more irritates you
раздражение больше вызывает у вас
irritates you
раздражает вызывает
not much  allocates for social services
н много выделяет на социалку
yes well there is a
да ну есть
point It's
момент
funny how to
Прикольно как это
say it I'm not a person who
сказать я не то чтобы человек который со
watches from the outside
стороны смотрит
but I would like it
но хотелось бы
not to be different But
чтобы не то что По иному вс проходило А
how how differently
как как по-иному
well what goes to your own goes to your own
ну то что на сво ходит это на сво уходит
I don't know  about this because I don't
Я не знаю про это потому что я и не
try to delve into
стараюсь вникать в
such global issues, otherwise I might
такие глобальные вопросы а то вдруг
accidentally delve into it and it will be bad.
случайно Вник неш и плохо будет
No,
Да нет
why? It would be possible, but I don't think it's
почему Можно было бы но я не считаю
necessary to do this. And why don't you think it's
нужным это делать А почему не считаете
necessary?
нужным
Well, I  A
Ну я Гражданский
civilian first of all
человек в первую очередь Так
So what can I think or judge about
а что я могу думать или судить о
anything all this will be history told
чём-либо всё это будет история сказано
years later And
спустя годы А на сегодняшний
today it is not for us to judge And who is to judge
день не нам судить И А кому судить
others think about
другие думают об
this to whom who are these other
этом кому кто эти другие
people who probably get money for this
люди которые за это наверное деньги
and those who work on this,
получают и которые работают над этим
those who deal with these
которые занимаются этими
issues, someone but not me, understood, someone but
вопросами кто-то но не я понял кто-то но
not me, a good
не я хорошая
topic. Well, I can't say that I have a weak
тема Ну я не могу сказать что я слабую
civil position.
гражданскую позицию
You have a very strong civil
занимаю у тебя очень сильная гражданская
position. I've already heard sarcasm. But this
позиция же уж слышала сарказм А вот
one, as it were.  distraction and scars on the face
такой как бы отвлечение а шрамы на лице
where
откуда
And once I got into an accident
А когда-то в аварию
my husband understood now where on his m TF no And
понял муж сейчас где на сво м ТФ нет А
where Thank God
где Слава богу
no not
нет не
here but
здесь а
where well somewhere
где ну где-то
he lives with you why should I say
он с тобой живёт почему должна говорить
what where and how starting with the fact that
что где и как начиная с того что
my salary we started to discuss its size
заработной платы мои мы начали размер её
now also with my husband
обсуждать сейчас ещё муже
Reduce Yes now we will also
Уменьши Да сейчас ещё и мужа будем
reduce my husband Well where
уменьшать Ну куда
at
у
somewhere somewhere This is
где-то где-то Это
where Well somewhere but not
где Ну где-то но не
nearby another m
рядом другой м
no with another
нет с другим
If especially
Если тем более
not a threesome he has
нет тройничок у него
there  I hope not, although anything
там Надеюсь нет хотя В жизни всякое
can happen in life.  to allow thoughts
бывает нельзя не допускать мысли о том
that anything can happen
что бывает
as the same as Crimea is ours
всякое как то же самое что и Крым наш
Sorry but this is already my
Извините но это уже мой
sarcasm You said before that
сарказм Вы до этого сказали о том что
a trolling
а троллить
a Ukrainian citizens yes If I
а украинских граждан да Если я правильно
understand correctly Yes And this is the
так понимаю Да И вот это вот
American flag and you are hanging it out
американский флаг и вы вывешивается по
the result of the conversation at the end and
итогу разговора в конце а
Russian
российский
Yes I'm not mistaken
Да я не ошиб
yes But honestly more aggression in the conversation
да Но честно больше агрессии в разговоре
and in relation to some Russian I heard from
а в отношении российских каких-то я от
you
вас
What was the aggression about but to
услышала В чём агрессия была проте но
me such shades seemed impossible I'm
мне оттенки такие показались не может я
wrong of course not you're wrong this is the case
не права конечно не вы не права это дело
in what you
в том что
are looking at you just see the negative this
смотрите Вы просто видите негатив этот
negative is in you, the pest, and that is why you
негатив у вас вредине сидит и поэтому вы
objectively evaluate the Russian Federation and
обектив оцениваю Российскую Федерацию н
Crimea is Ukraine Yes, the Russians are occupiers,
Крым это Украина Да россияне оккупанты
like well, I am without any negativity, clearly,
типа ну я без всякого негатива чётко
just normal You perceive
просто нормально Это вы воспринимаете
this as
это как
neho
нехо
arev this is vos as aggressive look at that
арев это вос как агрессив смотри то
that words can be aggressive
что слова бывают агрессивными
arev and vos you perceived aggressively
арев и вос ты восприняла агрессивно
because look you are looking for
потому что смотри ты ищешь
evil It's like Here is a bee She is looking for honey And a
зло Это как Вот пчела Она ищет мёд А
fly is always
муха всегда
looking here you are now me  I say words and you
ищет вот ты сейчас я говорю слова а ты
search
ищешь
You're like a fly searching for e
Ты как муха ищешь е
po Yes I just go
по Да я просто го
Putin is just a word And you see
Путин это просто слово А ты видишь в
negativity in this Bees
этом негатив
see positivity in this honey No, in the
Пчёлки видят в этом Позитив мёд Нет в
sense and only flies say
смысле и только мухи говорят
chu when they call it a square they have something
чу когда называют квадрат те что-то
stuck here between their teeth
застряло тут между зубами
Wait Yes yes something got stuck
Подожди Да да застряло
Black something ah
что-то Чёрное такое а
Well probably no no not a poppy seed or
Ну наверно нене не маковое зёрнышко или
something or a
что или лук
greenish onion Well what was that Well
зеленовато Ну а что это было Ну немножко
you can dig it out a little
можешь выкопай
m I'll brush my teeth in the morning got it Got it I'll get
м я почищу зубы утром понял Понял на
ready for work I'll brush them Okay Well
работу буду собираться я почищу О'кей Ну
at least with my tongue  somewhere it shifts then it
хотя бы языком где-то сдвинет то оно
interferes a little with talking yes yes Yeah oh
немножко мешает разговаривать да да Угу
already like A
о уже вроде А ну
oh well you started our conversation so beautifully
ладно вы так прекрасно начали разговор
at the beginning calling my eyes beautiful
наш в начале назвав мои глаза красивыми
I was very pleased and Thank you for the
Мне было очень приятно а Благодарю за
compliments don't thank me it wasn't a
комплименты не благодарите это был не
compliment it's just me getting into it
комплимент это я просто так вхожу в
Trust I even if I see someone Yes I
Доверие Я даже если вижу кого-то Да я
say something something nice to go
говорю что-то что-то приятное чтобы ийти
to  Trust and a conversation started this is such a
в Доверие и завязался разговор это такой
psychological technique Yeah I am a psychologist 18
психологический приём Ага я психолог 18
years of practice in 2 years will be the
лет практики через 2 года будет
twentieth
двадцатого
evil of course just outstanding
зла конечно прям выдающийся
Yes you can feel it in the conversation on the topic on the
Да чувствуется по разговору по теме по
dream again again Green this
сно снова снова Зелёная это
came out Well not general I can't help but pay attention
вылезла Ну не общ Я не могу не обращать
I want everything to be clear  Take
Я хочу чтобы всё было чётко Возьмите
a little of it with saliva, maybe it
пополо её немножко слюной может оно
will come off if you can't
отойдёт если не можете
dig it up, take more with the right
откопать наберите побольше с правильно
hug
обнимание
scars so
шрамы так
and I am grateful to you for what
а я благодарна вам за что
A for the fact that you are
А за то что вы
attentive
внимательны
but how to say
но как сказать
there never need
тамм никогда не надо
how to express it to
как это выразиться
you you insulted me more in the conversation
вам вы меня больше оскорбили в разговоре
than  I even you yes I have never
чем я вас даже да я ни разу не
resorted Yes I agree on some topic
прибег Да какой-то тематике согласен
Absolutely right and in the conversation and I
Абсолютно верно и в разговоре и я
tried to be
пыталась
minimally
минимально
rude even no I was not rude Yes I know
грубить даже нет я не грубила Да я знаю
and I was rude And what Well you are a psychologist you
а я грубил И что Ну Вы психолог вам
know better I know better I can be
виднее мне виднее я могу
rude You can  there is to file a complaint to the
грубить Вы можете есть подать жалобу в
UN for example write that a psychologist from you
ООН например написать что психолог из
can write a complaint to my university
можете в мой университет написать жалобу
Yes what am I By the way they will consider yes what am I  I'm
Да что я его Кстати рассмотрят да что я
sitting in you begging
сижу в вас умоляю
Yalya about such
яля о таких
things Well, I don't even feel comfortable with it, it's all the same
вещах Ну мне даже неприятно мне ВС равно
Well, I do this by right of the strong
Ну я по праву сильного это
I wouldn't
делаю я бы не
say I want and I do and what should I
сказала хочу и делаю и что мне
do
сделать
But yes, that's the thing, that strength is that
А да вот в том-то и дело что сила в том
when a person can
что когда человек может нормально
talk normally adequately A and not
разговаривать адекватно А и не
react to any such things and
реагировать на какие-либо такие вещи а
you react more and more sharply much
вы реагируете больше и и острее намного
than I am an
чем я
adult you are
взрослый человек вам
40 or 37
40 или 37
65 then good you look very
65 тогда хорошо Вы выглядите очень
pretty wonderful Yes but as you say
довольно прекрасно Да но как вы говорите
Sacramento you work yes at the
Сакраменто работаете да в
university there the climate is very  good
университете там климат Очень хороший
very good
очень хороший
Echo very useful and women are
Ехо очень полезный а женщины
beautiful I'm sure
красивые уверено
tanned and tanned and not tanned
загорелые и загорелые и не загорелые
all sorts
всякие
are there positively I envy
есть положительно Завидую
you very interesting
вам интересно очень
probably How do you think why Russians are
наверное Как вы считаете почему россияне
such that they support the killing of people in
такие что поддерживают убийство людей в
Ukraine
Украине
and I don't
а не
know Well how are you Duma frankly scow I don't
знаю Ну как вы Дума откровенно скау не
know And I listened  your point of view
знаю А я выслушала вашу точку зрения
now
сейчас
but
а
frankly what should I
откровенно А что мне
say Well if you talk to yourself like that
сказать Ну если вы так себя
behave with you probably
разговариваете ведёте с вами наверное
well try to talk some kind of
хорошо пытаются разговаривать какой-то
dialogue conduct
диалог вести
and not I would not say there active or
а не я бы не сказала бы там активный или
something but
что-то а
positive Well if  here you
положительный Ну если вот вы сами
say it yourself You are trying to insult on the basis of force
говорите Вы на основании силы пытаетесь
and trying to be rude I did
оскорбить и пытаетесь нагрубить я вам
nothing bad to you
ничего плохого не
you attacked my
сделала вы напали на мою
country And I personally attacked Yes and zeros In
страну А я лично нападала Да а нули В
what context How do you say to
каком контексте Как вы говорите
look aggressively probably yes yes Well
агрессивно смотреть наверное да да Ну
what can I
что мне
say Well I attacked here I am  I run with a shovel
сказать Ну напала вот я бегаю с лопатой
and
и
attack you are a citizen of the Russian
нападая вы же Гражданка Российской
Federation you
Федерации вы
yes yes you attacked our
да да вы напали на нашу
country here I say again I run with a shovel
страну вот я ещё раз говорю я с лопатой
and right around the yard and just
бегаю и вот прям вокруг двора и только
hit the
вот прямо бью
snow with it I
ею по снегу я
attack yes my taxes are paid and
нападаю да на мои налоги оплачиваются и
theirs and  all that and
сво и всё такое и
what And I
что А у меня выбор
have a choice there is always a choice And did you go to the elections
есть выбор есть всегда А ты на выборы
by the way Elections Elections are individual for
кстати Выборы Выборы - это индивидуально
each person I ask did you go to the
каждого Челове Я спрашиваю ты ходила на
elections Of course I voted for each one for whom I
выборы Конечно я на каж за кого
voted And I am not
голосовала А я не
obliged And I am not obliged to answer  to this
обяза А я не обязана отвечать на этот
question Well, I'm interested Just why
вопрос Ну мне интересно Просто зачем
just Ira who did you
просто Ире за кого вы
vote for Trump You went to the
голосовали за трампа Вот вы ходили на
elections Yes, for
выборы Да за
Trump And in Ukraine you went to the elections I'm
трампа А на Украине выходили на выборы Я
not talking about Ukraine  I and you do not
же не в Украине говорю я а вы не
live but you are so worried about
проживаете но вы так переживаете за
Ukraine I am not a citizen of Ukraine I
Украину я не гражданин Украины Я
am asking you are you worried about
спрашиваю то вы вы переживаете за
Ukraine and es I am worried about Russia for
Украину а ес Я переживаю за Россию за
our mother Russia so that it finally
нашу Россию матушку чтобы она наконец-то
falls apart we
уже короче развалилась мы такими словами
have spoken such ugly words about Russia
некрасивыми высказались про Россию
and then  there is the president of the Russian Federation
а то есть президент Российской Федерации
is first and foremost the face of the
является в первым очередь лицом
Russian Federation of the Russian
Российской Федерации Российской
Federation That's it, that's the face Yes, this is the
Федерации Вот вот вот лицо Да лицо это
face Yes, you are representatives of the Russian
лицо Да вы представители Российской
Federation This is
Федерации Это Ваше
your face This is your face Yes, your
лицо Это Ваше лицо Да Ваше
face is the face of a dictator's face of people
лицо лицо диктаторского лицо человеко
haters thirsts for blood wants to kill the
ненавистников жаждет крови хочет убить
more people in the world to capture  the whole
чем больше людей в мире захватить весь
world is your face This is your face on you
мир это Ваше лицо Это Ваше лицо на вы
who came to Ukraine to kill people
которые пришли в Украину убивать людей
you destroyed Bakhmut solidarity Mariupol
вы уничтожили бахмут солидар Мариуполь
bomb Kharkov Kiev Lvov And the souls of
бомбить Харьков Киев Львов Да и души
these children of people they will come to
этих детей людей они будут приходить ко
all of you Russians in the morning afternoon and evening At
всем вам россиянам утром днём и вечером
night not letting you sleep How many
Ночью не давать спать Сколько сколько
Russians already  committed
уже россиян покончили жизнь
suicide because of this because the
самоубийствам из-за этого из-за того что
souls of Ukrainian children come to them and
приходят к ним души украинских детей и
ask Why bomb Donbass Why
спрашивают Зачем бомбить Донбасс Зачем
bomb Donbass you 10  years bombed
бомбить Донбасс вы 10 лет бомбили
Donbass 10 years already alley of angels these are all
Донбасс 10 лет уже аллея ангелов это все
citizens of Ukraine who died from Russian
граждане Украины погибшие от российской
aggression m strange for some reason barks when you
агрессии м странно почему-то коры при
sit in Russia you sit in Russia and
сидите в России вы сидите в России да
kill people in Ukraine and also
убиваете людей в Украине да и ещё
say And why are you aggressive towards us
Говорите А почему вы к нам агрессирует
because you started on  you
потому что вы начали на нас агрессию вы
attacked our country with aggression and you sit there like you
напали на нашу страну и вы сидите такие
know like flies
знаете как мухи
and like And why don't you like us here
на и такие А что это вы тут нас не
because these are flies and no
любите так потому что это мухи и
one likes flies and no one
это никто не любит мух и никто не
likes and especially no one likes flies and that's the
любит а тем более никто не любит мух
point  in that if flies if flies
на и дело в том если мухи если бы мухи
were where they are in their this would be
были там где они в своём этом это было б
one thing and flies fly They
одно а мухи летят Они
fly to flower beds they fly
прилетают на цветочные клумбы прилетают
into people's houses they fly everywhere they fly and
людям в дома прилетают всюду они летят и
spread this infection all over the world
разносят эту заразу по всему миру если
if this Russian world sat there at home  and
бы этот русский мир сидел там у себя и
didn't climb out then everything would be fine if he sat
не вылазил то всё было бы хорошо сидел
there, let him I don't know at least
бы там пусть не знаю хоть с опарышами
eat each other with maggots but you climb fly
съедали друг друга но вы лезете летите
to discuss But this  it doesn't make any sense it does
дискутировать Но это смысла никакого не
n't make any sense psychologist
имеет никакого не имеет психолог
yes you are a psychologist you uh like before
да Вы психолог вы э как до этого минут
10 minutes ago you said that in my opinion
10 назад высказались в том что по моей
Mika's face again again this thing again
Мики лица снова снова эта штучка снова
this thing well fix it fix it again it's
эта штука ну поправь её поправь бы снова
out did you eat dill maybe or mint or
она выле это ты укроп ела может или мяту
something  it's
что это
like rosemary probably rosemary well
такое розмарин наверное розмарин ну
take it away Yes a little well it's coming out Well
забери его Да немножко ну он вылазит Ну
well it's unpleasant that rosemary a piece of
ну неприятно что розмарин кусочек
green my eyesight is just good
зелёного у ме просто зрение хорошее
take after
возьми сле
them from your teeth run your tongue over your teeth
их с зубов проведи языком по зубам
let me talk like this it
давайте я так буду разговаривать вам
will be more comfortable for you Give yes Yeah
удобнее будет Дай да Угу
okay you're a psychologist and so  you talk
хорошо Вы психолог и так разговариваете
yes And what then can you teach
да А чему тогда вы можете научить
students How to talk to Russians
студентов Как разговаривать с россиянами
I have a whole course like that in the
У меня целый курс такой есть на
department
кафедре
m and what is the name of your course
м а как курс называется ваш
Russophobia for beginners
русофобия для начинающих
Well, for some reason I thought so something
А ну я почему-то так и подумала что-то
similar should be the name
похожее должно быть название
[music]
[музыка]
a  But you are not an
а Но вам не взрослый
adult, this is not just one course, there are
человек это не только один курс есть ещё
other courses at another faculty, I teach Well, there is a
разные на другом факультете веду Ну там
more advanced course, yes, the basics of
более продвинутый курс да ээ основы
Russophobia for students, and
русофобии для студентов э
psychologists, practical  Russophobia exists
психологов практическая русофобия есть
yes the
да
younger generation yes there is a section
подрастающее поколение да есть э раздел
for those who are preparing diplomats
для тех кто готовится дипломаты
Russophobia international politics
русофобии международной политики
Yeah Well it's very
Угу Ну очень
sad what can I
грустно что я могу
say Listen and another interesting
сказать Слушайте а ещё такой интересный
question Why in our Russia there is oil
вопрос Почему в нашей России есть нефть
gas gold diamonds the richest country and
газ золото алмазы богатейшая страна а
people live
люди живут
poorly
бедно
m I don't know  I don't live poorly
м я не знаю я бедно не живу бедно
you live poorly you don't have enough Why do we have a
живёшь не хватает Ну почему у нас в
salary of 99,000 dollars in America you have a
Америке 99.000 долларов зарплата у тебя
salary of 500 dollars and the North is
500 долларов зарплата и Север
terrible Why is the North terrible it's cold
Ужасный А почему Север ужасный холодина
And so on Yes they should pay
И так дальше Да там должны доплачивать
more there ho No it's just that in Sacramento
больше хо Нет просто в Сакраменто там
the sun shines there it's like the South  it's warm and
солнышко светит там Южное как бы тепло а
here it's cold This is
здесь холодно Это в
due to the arctic conditions It's purely
силу арктических условий Это чисто
geo how can I say it geophysical or Well
гео как это сказать геофизическое или Ну
it's just such climatic conditions Yeah It's
это просто климатические условия такие
cold here
Угу Здесь холодно вот
that's why And what else is
поэтому А в чём ещё
terrible Well for example we have the state of
ужасно Ну например у нас есть штат
Alaska it's
Аляска там
colder there No it's warmer there it's warmer yes
холоднее на Нет там теплее там теплее да
and  Well, in theory,
а ну по идее
the salary there is 15 times more than
а зарплата там 15 раз больше чем у
yours.
вас
Well, I dont know. I havent
Ну не знаю Я там не
lived there. How do I feel?  judge if I haven't
жила как мне судить если я там не
lived there, here you have a salary of 9,000
жила вот у вас заработная плата 9.000
dollars Yes, probably very
долларов Да наверное очень
good Not very good but good Where are you going to go on
хорошо Не очень но хорошо А куда поедете
vacation?
отдыха
We vacation in California We have the
мы отдыхаем в Калифорнии У нас тут самые
best beaches here You can also go to Hawaii I
лучшие пляжи есть ещё можно на гавай я
flew to Hawaii
летал на гавай
to vacation for 99,000, yes probably  you can
отдыхать ну на 99.000 да наверно можно
go Well, I didn't think about
съездить Ну я не думала об
it probably because
этом наверно ввиду того что у
I have a small salary
меня маленькая заработная плата
and a
и
small salary Well, not
жение Ну не
9,000 compared to 9,000 dollars
9.000 по сравнению с 9.000 долларами у
I have a small salary but I'm
меня маленькая заработная плата но я
happy with it And with imagination What are you
этим довольна А с воображением Что вы
saying And little imagination
говорите И мало воображение
M I can't imagine  what is
М не могу представить себе что такое
Miami or Hawaii and what do they look like I've
Майами или Гавайи и как они выглядят Я
only seen it in movies and on TV
только в фильмах видела и по телевизору
Can you imagine okay Miami
А можете представить хорошо ладно Майами
and Hawaii you can't imagine but can you
и гавай не можете представить а можете
imagine Anapa Gelendzhik
представить Анапу Геленджик
Novorossiysk or also only saw it in a movie
Новороссийск или тоже только по фильме
no passing through
видел нет проездом
okay Maybe you saw Magadan in
была хорошо Может видели Магадан в
art Here  by the way I've never been to these parts.
арту Вот кстати в эти края меня не
That's why,
заносила ни разу Вот почему-то
how old is the girl  and for me it
вот а сколько м лет девушка а мне
is enough
достаточно
how much so that I can travel around the central
сколько чтобы я могла объездить среднюю
part of
полосу
Russia
России
how much And you how much 43 And you
сколько А вам сколько 43 А вы мне
will be older than me I thought younger in view of the
постарше будете Я думала помоложе ввиду
fact that your
того что ваших
reasoning how much
рассуждений сколько
[music] to
[музыка]
you Well approximately how much and for you it is not
вам Ну приблизительно сколько и вам не
real here every year plays a role
реально тут каждый год играет роль
m I don't even  I know what to answer you I'm
м я даже не знаю что вам ответить Я
afraid It's just that if I say I'll get
боюсь Просто если я скажу я опять получу
some kind of
какой-то
And in
А в
relation to
отношении
myself
себя
opus And you
опус А ты быстро
learn quickly you're quite like She's a capable
учишься ты довольно как Она способная
student yes
ученица да
Yes I wouldn't say that Yes you already understand
Да я бы так не сказала Да уже понимаешь
what's going on okay two don't break say
к чему идёт ладно два не ломайся говори
how much  you and I'm not being pushy tell me
сколько тебе а я не ломаюсь говори
how
сколько
old I told you how old you are
лет Я же сказала сколько же и вам
and I'm the same I'm 43 you're not 43 you're
столько и мне мне 43 тебе не 43 тебе
younger Yes
меньше Да чуть-чуть помладше сейчас
we'll be a little younger now how about
будем как с
the salary Well yes
зарплатой Ну да на 20%
take off 20% g 20% is 1/5 -  8 years somewhere
снимай г 20% - это 1/5 -8 Лет где-то
in short you are
короче тебе
No, still more than
Нет ещё сни побольше
approximately
приблизительно
cool well you look
прикольно ну ты выглядишь
younger Well somewhere around 50 I know Well I  I
помоложе Ну где-то на 50 знаю А ну я
expected something
ожидала такое
like this Well, I wouldn't be a psychologist
подобное Ну я же не был бы психологом
if it were
если бы
n't for that What do you think Well, Putin is a man of
нет Как ты считаешь Ну Путин человек
his word that Putin is a man of
слова что Путин человек
his word I don't
слово я ничего не
think anything do you like
считаю тебе нравится
Putin Yes and do you like him as a man like
Путин Да а как мужчина он тебе нравится
me I didn't consider this option
м как я Не рассматривала такого вариант
Well, if you consider it like this
Ну если рассмотреть вот так
hypothetically hypothetically I don't
гипотетически гипотетически я не
consider for me e politicians that as a
рассматриваю для меня э политики что как
teacher I don't consider them from the point of
учителя я их не рассматриваю с точки
view of male or female variation for
зрения мужской или женского вариации для
me these are personalities Well, let's say such a
меня это личности Ну вот скажем такая
person as Putin He is sexually
личность как Путин Он сексуально
attractive
привлекательный
and I say again I can't
а я ещё раз говорю я не могу
consider them from that point of view  point of view And
рассматривать их с такой точки зрения А
from
с
what point of view
какой
And once again I confirm How from the point of view of the
А ещё раз Подтверждаю Как с точки зрения
character's personality Describe this
личности персонажа э Опиши этого
character Putin from the point of view of the
персонажа Путина с точки зрения
personality historically strong personality And
личности исторически сильная личность А
what is his strength
в чём его сила
In what Yes in the fact
В чём Да в том
that the person who held on to power for
что человек который удержался власти
so many years and carried out his
столько лет и произвёл свои
reforms and moreover meaningfully
реформы и причём многозначительно
can you name an example of the reforms that Putin
можешь пример реформ который Путин
has carried out, there are
провёл
quite a few of them,
назвать их довольно-таки много
they are simply the most meaningful, most likely,
просто самые многозначительно они скорее
yes, in a few years they will
всего да спустя несколько лет они будут
already be designated specifically, this is like in
уже обозначены конкретно это как во
Stolypin's time, they also wanted to kill him
времена Столыпина его же тоже убить
again, Putin has been
хотели ещё раз ещё раз Путин с 2000 года
in power since 2000  25 years will be soon
при власти уже 25 лет скоро будет
yes What are his reforms in these 25 years they
да В чём его реформы за эти 25 лет их
can already be seen in the World Cup
уже можно увидеть в ЧМ
reforms Well I saw the retirement age
реформы Ну видел пенсионный возраст
was raised So what else
повысили Так а что ещ
No well the retirement age
Не ну пенсионный возраст увеличить его
had to be raised Well here it can't be helped
надо было Ну тут уже как бы не поделаешь
here a slightly different situation is needed
тут немножко другая иная ситуация надо
look at it differently
смотреть по-другому
and there are
а трудоспособного населения
quite a
довольно-таки
lot of working-age people retiring then what
много на пенсию выходить людям то В чём
Yes name at least one interesting
Да назови хоть одну какую-то интересную
reform
реформу
What is
В чём реформа
Putin's reform Putin's reform
Путина реформа Путина в
what Putin has done in 25
чём что Путин сделал за 25
years Well besides
лет Ну помимо того что Конституцию
changing the Constitution Well okay that  you can also let it go
поменял Ну ладно это тоже можно пустить
without even thinking about
даже не задумываться об
it I don't want to discuss it it's not my
этом я не хочу обсуждать это не в моий
prerogative I am
прерогативы я
Putin you said that Putin Yes made
Путин ты сказала что Путин Да сделал
reforms for his reforms yes what at least
реформы за его реформы да то какие хоть
one reform name him in 25 years what did you
одну реформу назови его за 25 лет что ты
feel what
ощутила какую
[music]
[музыка]
reform I still  since I say I have no right to
реформу я ещё раз говорю я не имею права
comment you are prohibited by the Constitution from
комментировать тебе в Конституции
commenting No I am prohibited because
комментировать Нет мне запрещено ввиду
I have no right to speak and
Я не имею права говорить и
discuss any actions at all
обсуждать вообще любые
who prohibited you who said
действия кто тебе запретил кто сказал
that you do not have
что ты не имеешь
rights And why should they
права А почему должны
say who said you have no right to
говорить кто сказал ты не имеешь права
answer the question What reforms a
ответить на вопрос Какие реформы
freely speaking
свободно говорящий
person in the sense of not freely And who is a
человек в смысле не свободно А кто
person well if I was from Khatsapetovka before Bright
человек ну если бы я до яркой была из
probably yes and what kind of a non-
Хацапетовки наверное да а что ты за не
freely speaking person are you well
свободно говорящий человек ну потому
because  I can't I don't want so what did you
что я не могу не хочу так что ты плохое
say bad about Putin on the contrary good
сказала про Путина наоборот хорошее
praise never and I would never say bad
похвали никогда и не сказала бы плохого
look you are not a fluent speaker
смотри ты Не свободно говорящий человек
but you are good say good about Putin
но ты хорошая скажи хорошее про Путина
you will be praised for it you don't know what
тебя похвалят за это не вот знаете что
I
мне вот так
like about it by the way in a conversation with  you
нравится кстати в разговоре с вами
and I really liked The Fine Line
а мне очень понравилась Тонкая грань
When you said that you are a
Когда вы сказали что Вы
psychologist very much
психолог очень
and during our conversation I was
и в ходе нашего разговора Мне было
interested to hear
интересно услышать всё-таки
some kind of professionalism from your point of
профессионализм какой-то с вашей точки
view But besides aggression and conclusions on
зрения Но кроме агрессии и выводов на
provocations of any kind, this is also
провокации какие-либо так это есть тоже
aggression -  this is also a tool of a
агрессия - это тоже инструмент работы
psychologist but it is too uninteresting
психолога но он слишком неинтересен
perhaps the main thing is effective
возможно главно эффективен
Well and in what is it effective In what I
Ну а в чём он эффективен В чём меня
was led as a matter of fact I can say
вывели по сути дела Я могу сказать что
anything and do not even think
угодно и даже не задумываюсь
But honestly, in fact, in this dialogue
А честно вот по сути дела в этом диалоге
I am as frank as possible
я вот по максимальному откровенно
I'm talking but not because you're
разговариваю но не потому что вы меня
pissing me off but because I'm just too lazy to
выводите а потому что мне просто лень
lie to the wrong target audience you've
врать не на ту целевую аудиторию вы
somehow directed yours you're not my target
как-то направили свой не вы моя целевая
audience Yes I know you're the object with
аудитория Да я знаю Вы объект с помощью
which a product is made for the target
которого делается продукт для целевой
audience Well, what kind of product will it be  I'm
аудитории А ну и Какой продукт получится
no good, you evaluate yourself quite objectively
никакой вы довольно объективно себя
Well, let's look at it from this point of view
А ну хорошо давайте так с этой точки
I'm not inferior to you in let's do
я не уступаю вам по давайте мы сделаем
a little bit like that after all We
немножко так уже всё-таки Мы довольно
spent quite a lot of time on this product,
много потратили на этот продукт
sucked out of you everything that can be
времени высосали из вас всё что можно
sucked out, yes, in the informational  on the planet
высосать да в информационном плане
uh let's
ээ
say about the negative on you everything that can be
скажем по негативе на вас всё что можно
understood Vit Yes and I think it's time to move
поне Вить Да и я думаю что время идти
on you know how a
дальше знаете как
bee stayed on a
пчела побыла на
leaf and took Yes Took honey flies further
листочке взяла Да Взяла мёд летит дальше
and the flies all sit in their own we had
а мухи сидят все в своём у нас были
psychologists who came And by the way here
психологи которые приезжали И кстати вот
uh here they told  the story is that I
э вот рассказывали историю в том что
like how this Legend I listened and
нравится как эта Легенда я слушала и
watched I thought damn What kind of
смотрела думаю блин Что за
[music] is this
[музыка]
nonsense Well, the truth is
бред Ну вот правда
that I dont know Im even embarrassed to discuss
что я не знаю Мне даже стно обсуждать
anything Ill go  I will find a fluent
что-либо я пойду найду свободно
speaker
говорящего человека
Okay
Окей
Okay I am not a fluent speaker
О'кей я не свободно говорящий человек
so fluent speakers like
так свободно говорящие люди лайк
subscribe comment and send a video to
подписка комен и скиньте видео свободно
other fluent speakers Glory to
говорящим другим людям Слава
Ukraine subscribe to y Telegram right
Украине подпишись на й Telegram прям
now axis VN
зараз ось ВН
apok this is very and very important YouTube is busy
апок це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня
with us through the SRG ORV in  your ban and very
нас через срг ОРВ в твый бан и дуже
many videos I don't show to people sometimes I don't
багато видео не показую людям вчасно не
show information about streams so
показуе информация про стримы тому для
that we Mali operational links
того щоб ми Мали оперативный звязок
are written right now and Popik there in
пишиться прямо зараз а Попик там в
telegrams okrim video also interesting and
телеграми окрим видео ще теж е цикава и
useful information and we are sorry for you
корисна информация и мы повинни з вами
constant operational links
тримати постийний оперативный звязок
independently  in that chi will show you about this
незалежно в того чи покаже вам про це
YouTube Glory to Ukraine
YouTube Слава Украине
write a
пиши а